

Email sam@stelfox.net

Site https://stelfox.net/

LinkedIn https://linkedin.com/in/samstelfox

ABOUT ME

As an experienced software engineer, I am passionate about security and data analysis. My background in operations provides me with unique insights into designing easy-to-run and diagnose systems.

I excel in fast-paced environments and have strong communication skills for conveying complex technical concepts. I value positive team culture and enjoy mentoring junior colleagues and contributing to a supportive work environment.

SKILLS

| ● ● ● ● Rust, Ruby, Python, Data Analytics, Distributed System Design, Mentoring |
|--|
|--|

- ● ○ Kubernetes, AWS, Terraform, Networking, Data Quality & Governance
- ● ○ Javascript, TypeScript, Compliance

EXPERIENCE

Minim Inc | Remote

July 2022 - Present

Staff Software Engineer

- Lead the design, development, and deployment of a globally distributed filtering DNS network written in Rust
- Provided one-on-one and group training to colleagues on various topics ranging from programming languages to networking fundamentals
- Reviewed and developed internal processes, procedures, and policies to get Minim SOC2 Type 2 compliance

Minim Inc | Remote

April 2018 - July 2022

Senior Software Engineer

- Designed detection mechanisms for known and novel security threats by analyzing large volumes of telemetry
- Built up a cloud platform API handling ingestion, processing, and reporting of telemetry from 100k+ deployed devices
- Worked with business leadership to reduce costs by isolating and optimizing hot spots in our data pipeline
- Built on-premise version of our production platform inside of private data centers with maintenance, observability, and off-site diagnostics in mind
- Coordinated and organized internal security processes, incident responses, audits, vulnerability reports, and compliance

Rapid Focus Security Inc, dba PwnieExpress | Hybrid

February 2013 - April 2018

Senior Software Engineer

- Built core company product offerings from original MVP through post acquisition
- Managed company relations as a dedicated point of contact for special projects, audits, and on-site analysis
- Designed and built embeddeded Linux security appliances and centralized platform for management

Democracy for America | In Person

January 2012 - February 2013

Ruby Software Engineer

- Took charge of a 150k+ line legacy codebase, migrating and transitioning it to a modern Rails app
- Worked with diverse and distributed co-workers to provide unique tooling to optimize their jobs
- Built systems to collate and clean-up disparate dirty data systems into cohesive systems for analysis

Network and Systems Engineer

• Responsible for a mixed Windows and Linux environment across 13 physical sites

AFFILIATIONS

DEFCON July 2009 - Present

Speaker Operations - Lead

- Responsible for overseeing five main stages of content
- Coordination of 35 team members to ensure smooth operations during a high-demanding event
- Main interface with external vendors such as conference space and AV contractors to resolve issues

Vermont Hackerspaces, Inc

September 2011 - August 2017

Founder, Board Member, President

- Handled the registration, finances, fund-raising, and day-to-day operations of the non-profit
- Developed a network of sites throughout Vermont with local leadership
- Coordinated major events that operated as public outreach, and funding sources

EDUCATION

Bachelor Program in Software Engineering

Vermont Technical College

2005 - 2009